Guide to the Clarence W. Rowley Papers Relating to Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Clarence W. Rowley papers relating to Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan
1878-1941
1910-1920
WA MSS S-2513
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
4.09
(7 boxes)
Correspondence, photographs, printed material and other papers relating to Rowley and his relationships with Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan. Rowley's correspondence includes letters and telegrams concerning the development of property in Arizona, the dissolution of the Dyer-Cody Arizona Mining and Milling Company following a financial scandal in 1911, and the subsequent incorporation of the High Jinks Gold Mining Company to recoup losses. Correspondence between Cody and Rowley details their friendship and investment partnership. Also includes a small set of letters written to William B. Gale of the Boston law firm Gale & Gale, dated 1878 to 1882, from various legal figures; correspondence related to John L. Sullivan's death in 1918; and correspondence concerning Buffalo Bill's posthumous reputation, including letters between Rowley and General Charles King, who served with Cody in the Indian Wars, recollecting Buffalo Bill's campaign experiences. In a letter dated 1930 Jan 3, Gordon "Pawnee Bill" Lillie tells Rowley about the establishment of Pawnee, Oklahoma, his western entertainment venture. There is also a letter to Rowley from John L. Sullivan shortly before Sullivan's death in 1917. Photographs include formal portraits of Clarence Rowley, as well as photographs of Rowley mining, traveling, at home and with friends. Hundreds of photographs relate to Rowley's trips West and to Buffalo Bill and his Wild West show. Candid and staged photographs, several captioned and autographed in Buffalo Bill's own hand, include portraits with his wife Louisa, photos of the TE Ranch, and snapshots of a tour of Camp Bliss with General Hugh L. Scott in 1914. Photographs relating to John L. Sullivan date from 1882 to 1910. Most are publicity shots picturing Sullivan in boxing poses, in the ring, or with other famous athletes. Includes a series of photos taken in 1910 at the James Jeffries vs. Jack Johnson fight in Reno, Nevada. Many of the other photographs picture Sullivan as an older man on his farm in Massachusetts. There is also a set of photographs documenting a meeting between Buffalo Bill and Sullivan in 1908. Clarence Rowley's personal papers include eleven diaries from 1909 to 1919. The diaries contain brief daily notes on business and personal matters such as court dates, social functions, the births of Rowley's children, and Rowley's travels, including a 1911 trip with Cody. Rowley's business papers include incorporation documents, by-laws, minutes and other papers of the High Jinks Gold Mining Company; stock certificates, shareholder resolutions, and reports of the Montezuma Silver Mine Company; and a description of the John L. Sullivan Motion Picture Company. Remaining Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan material is arranged in subject files, and includes printed material, clippings, speeches, and writings related to the two men. Buffalo Bill material includes a folio of six chromolithograph prints titled The Indian: Buffalo Bill's Art Studies with Portraits of Himself. Other papers include a Henry Ward Beecher autograph, a report on the Campo Bonito and Southern Belle Mining and Milling Company by F.E. Fielding, and a printed prospectus for the Cripple Creek Consolidated Mining and Milling Company.
Rowley, Clarence W.
Fielding, F. E. ( Report on the Campo Bonito and Southern Belle Mining and Milling Company, Pinal County, Arizona)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The papers were purchased from William Reese Co. on the Frederick W. and Carrie S. Beinecke Fund for Western Americana, 2004.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
CLARENCE W. ROWLEY
Clarence W. Rowley was a successful Boston lawyer who represented both William F. "Buffalo Bill" Cody and boxing champion John L. Sullivan. Early in his career, Rowley ran for a seat on the Boston Common Council. A circular promoting his candidacy to voters of Ward 18 noted that he was a "self-made man" whose family had resided in New England "for more than two centuries."
An investor in several mining and oil ventures in the West, Rowley was an officer, major stockholder, and chief legal representative for the Cody-Dyer Arizona Mining and Milling Company in Oracle, Arizona. When the company dissolved after financial troubles in 1911, Rowley and Cody founded the High Jinks Gold Mining Company to recoup losses. Rowley was also involved in the Southern Belle gold mining company in Arizona and the Montezuma Silver Mine Corporation in Goldfield, Nevada, and had some association with the Cripple Creek mine in Colorado.
Rowley maintained a friendship with Cody, and toured the West at his invitation in 1911. He was also business partners with John L. Sullivan, becoming Secretary and Treasurer of the John L. Sullivan Motion Picture Company when it was incorporated in 1917. He served as executor of Sullivan's estate after Sullivan's death in 1918.
Scope and Contents
The Clarence W. Rowley Papers Relating to Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan contain correspondence, photographs, diaries, printed material, newspaper clippings, and memorabilia documenting the life of Clarence W. Rowley, particularly his relationship with William F. "Buffalo Bill" Cody and John L. Sullivan. The papers span the dates 1878-1941, but the bulk of the material covers the years 1910-1920.
Series I, Correspondence (Box 1) is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Third-Party Correspondence. Both are arranged alphabetically by correspondent. General correspondence contains letters and telegrams concerning Rowley's business and personal relationships. They concern the development of property in Arizona, the dissolution of the Dyer-Cody Arizona Mining and Milling Company following a financial scandal in 1911, and the subsequent incorporation of the High Jinks Gold Mining Company. Letters between Cody and Rowley detail their friendship and their business partnerships. Correspondence between Rowley and General Charles King documents Rowley's attempts to protect Buffalo Bill's posthumous reputation, and relates King's recollections regarding Buffalo Bill's campaign experience. A letter from Gordon "Pawnee Bill" Lillie in 1930 describes the establishment of Pawnee, Oklahoma, a western entertainment venture. Third-party Correspondence contains a small set of letters written to William B. Gale of the Boston law firm Gale & Gale, dated 1878 to 1882, from various legal figures; a letter written to John L. Sullivan in 1917; and a letter concerning debts from A. L. Brown to A. Rossi, possibly related to one of Rowley's business ventures in the Southwest.
Series II, Photographs (Boxes 2-4) is organized into five subseries: Clarence W. Rowley, Buffalo Bill, Buffalo Bill's Wild West and Pawnee Bill's Great East Show, John L. Sullivan, and Other Photographs. The series contains both gelatin silver prints and cyanotypes. Clarence Rowley subseries contains formal portraits of Rowley, as well as photographs of Rowley mining, traveling, at home, and with friends. A set of photographs documents the meeting Rowley arranged between Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan in 1908. There are also many photographs of Rowley with Buffalo Bill, possibly taken during their 1911 tours; photographs of Rowley with various Wild West performers; a photograph of Rowley eating a camp meal with Theodore Roosevelt and others; and four photographs of Rowley's daughter, Patricia Ann Rowley.
Buffalo Bill subseries contains formal portraits, snapshots and postcards of Buffalo Bill and his family, including five photographs documenting Cody's tour of Fort Bliss, Texas, with General Hugh L. Scott. Buffalo Bill's Wild West and Pawnee Bill's Great East Show subseries contains over fifty photographs of performers, and includes two photographs of exhibition grounds. John L. Sullivan subseries contains studio portraits and commercial prints of Sullivan as both a young and an older man, including photographs with his wife and family, and a numbered group of photographs relating to the July 4, 1910 boxing match in Reno, Nevada, between Jack Johnson and James Jeffries.
Other Photographs subseries contains a set of albumen prints on mounts created by Allen & Rowell, Boston, reproducing scenes from Paul Philippoteaux's Battle of Gettysburg mural, as well as snapshots and miniature photographs of unidentified animals, individuals, landscapes, and objects.
Series III, Personal Papers (Box 5) is arranged by type of material. It contains a circular relating to Rowley's bid for a seat on the Boston Common Council, business stationery, a clipping, and a group of diaries which Rowley kept from 1909 to 1919.
Series IV, Business Papers (Boxes 5-6) is organized into four subseries: High Jinks Gold Mining Company, John L. Sullivan Motion Picture Company, Montezuma Mining Company, and Montezuma Silver Mines Corporation. Each subseries is arranged by type of material. High Jinks Gold Mining Company subseries contains incorporation documents, by-laws, minutes, and notes. John L. Sullivan Motion Picture Company subseries contains a description of the business. Montezuma Mining Company subseries and Montezuma Silver Mines Corporation subseries both contain stock certificates and other corporate documents.
Series V, Subject Files (Box 6) is organized into two subseries: Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan. Buffalo Bill subseries contains a biographical sketch, clippings tracing Buffalo Bill's career and commemorating his death, and a folio of six chromolithograph prints titled The Indian: Buffalo Bill's Art Studies with Portraits of Himself. John L. Sullivan subseries contains clippings, printed ephemera, typescript speeches and poems, and records related to the settlement of Sullivan's estate.
Series VI, Other Papers (Box 6) is arranged alphabetically by type or title of material. The series includes a Henry Ward Beecher autograph, a report on the Campo Bonito and Southern Belle Mining and Milling Company by F.E. Fielding, a printed prospectus for the Cripple Creek Consolidated Mining and Milling Company, and a typescript resolution from the "citizens of Boston... assembled in Faneuil Hall" urging the United States to send an "expeditionary force of volunteers under the command of Theodore Roosevelt to France to co-operate with the allied forces in the war against the Imperial German government."
Oversize contains material from Series I, II, and V. It includes oversize advertisements, photographs, and prints.
Boxers (Sports) -- United States -- Pictorial works; Boxing matches -- Nevada -- Reno; Indians of North America -- Pictorial works; Mines and mineral resources -- Arizona -- Pinal County; Mines and mineral resources -- Colorado -- Teller County; Campo Bonito (Ariz.) -- Pictorial works; Cody (Wyo.) -- Pictorial works; Cripple Creek (Colo.) -- Pictorial works; Fort Bliss (Tex.) -- Pictorial works; Goldfield (Nev.) -- Pictorial works; Oracle (Ariz.); TE Ranch (Cody, Wyoming) -- Pictorial works; Albumen prints; Cyanotypes (photographic prints); Diaries -- Massachusetts -- Boston -- 20th Century; Photographic postcards; Photographic prints; Speeches (documents); Stock certificates -- Nevada -- Esmeralda -- 20th Century; Lawyers -- Massachusetts -- Boston; Indian: Buffalo Bill's art studies with portraits of himself; Studio portraits; Buffalo Bill, 1846-1917; Pawnee Bill, 1860-1942; Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887; Cody, Louisa Frederici, 1843-1921; Dyer, D. B., Mrs.; Gale, William B.; Jeffries, James J., 1875-1953; Johnson, Jack, 1878-1946; King, Charles, 1844-1933; Rowley, Clarence W.; Scott, Hugh Lenox, 1853-1934; Sullivan, John Lawrence, 1858-1918; Buffalo Bill's Wild West Company -- Pictorial works; Campo Bonito and Southern Belle Mining and Milling Company; Cripple Creek Consolidated Mining and Milling Company; Dyer-Cody Arizona Mining and Milling Company; High Jinks Mining and Development Co; John L. Sullivan Motion Picture Company; Montezuma Silver Mine Company; Montezuma Silver Mines Corporation; Buffalo Bill's Wild West and Pawnee Bill's Great Far East (Show); Beecher, Henry Ward, 1813-1887 -- Autograph
- Correspondence, 1878-1941; Series I; 0.42; (1 box)
  Scope and Contents
  Series I, Correspondence, is organized into two subseries: General Correspondence and Third Party Correspondence. Each subseries is arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - GENERAL CORRESPONDENCE
    - Anderson, Bob, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Arizona Corporation Committee, 1912 Jul 20 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Baker, John, 1912, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Briggs, Richard, 1912 Aug 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Buffalo Bill, 1911-1914 (Box 1, Folder 5-7)
    - Burke, Charles H., 1929 Jan 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Cosby, Arthur F., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Cushing, John J., 1918 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Draft AL to unidentified recipient regarding Cody-Dyer Arizona Mining Company and Southern Belle mine (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Drovers National Bank, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dyer, D. B., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
    - Fitzsimmons, Joseph J., 1918 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Gilmore & Brown, 1912 May 25 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Hartman, Frances, 1912 Mar 23 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - High Jinks Gold Mining Company, 1912 Oct 23 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - "Jack", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Jeffreys, L. A., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - John L. Sullivan Banquet Committee, 1917 Nov 26 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Kerr, Alex, 1912 Jun 18 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - King, Charles, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Knoblauch, Charles E., 1912 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Ladd, P. P., 1912-1913 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Lowe, J. D., 1929 Jan 21 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Myles, Cash, 1911 Dec 25 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Pawnee Bill, 1930 Jan 3 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore, 1917 May 3 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Seymour, Edmund, 1941 Mar 22 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - Southern Arizona Bank Trust Company, 1912 Mar 13 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - Sullivan, John L., 1917 Nov 3 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Tucke, E. M., 1912 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - Winch, Frank, 1929 Feb 6 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - Zitlau, Emil, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - Empty envelopes, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Folder labels, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - THIRD PARTY CORRESPONDENCE
    - Brown, A. L. to A. Rossi, 1912 Jul 14 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Gale & Gale, 1878-1892, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Hanff, Joseph H. to John L. Sullivan, 1917 Jul 13 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      Related Archival Materials note
      See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 188
- Photographs, 1870-1938; Series II; 1.25; (3 boxes)
  Series II, Photographs, is organized into 5 subseries: Clarence W. Rowley, Buffalo Bill, Buffalo Bill's Wild West and Pawnee Bill's Great Far East (Show), John L. Sullivan, and Other Photographs. Each subseries, except John L. Sullivan, is arranged alphabetically by supplied title. The John L. Sullivan subseries is arranged chronologically.
  - CLARENCE W. ROWLEY
    - Arizona
      - Anasazi cliff dwellings (16 photographs), [1911?] (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - With Buffalo Bill at Campo Bonito (6 photographs), 1911 Nov 25 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Cripple Creek Consolidated Mining
      - Five mounted photographs: two with mines labeled in white ink, n.d.
    - Family
      - Rowley, Patricia Ann (4 photos), 1931 Oct 11 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Friends and Associates
      - Group photographs (9 photographs, 1 cyanotype), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 44-45)
      - [Mesher?], Ezra in Brookline, Mass., 1928 Aug (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Turner, Dr. A. W., n.d. (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - In desert, with cowboys and alone (2 photographs) (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - In pilot uniform, with unidentified pilot and plane (6 photographs) (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Meeting between Buffalo Bill and John L. Sullivan (7 photographs, 9 cyanotypes), 1908 (Box 2, Folder 50-51)
    - Mining
      - Alone (4 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 52-53)
      - Montezuma Mining Company, Goldfield, Nev. (23 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 54-55)
      - Unidentified people and mines (8 photographs, 4 cyanotypes) (Box 2, Folder 56-57)
    - Portraits by Elmer Chickering
      - On horse, n.d.
      - Seated, 1905
    - Property, gardening (5 photographs, 5 cyanotypes), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 58-59)
    - Roosevelt, Theodore. Eating camp meal with group of men and a woman near lake (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Seated with Richard Currie (1 photograph, 3 cyanotypes), 1906 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Spalding, Freddie. Posed kneeling with rope (Box 2, Folder 62)
      Autographed.
    - Wagon trip (10 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - With Buffalo Bill, standing and on horseback (7 photographs), [1911?] (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - With Buffalo Bill, Chief Iron Tail and unidentified Native Americans from Buffalo Bill's Wild West (10 photographs) (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - With Buffalo Bill, Johnny Baker, and unidentified man, standing outside show grounds (2 photographs) (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - With cowboy performer, in cowboy dress, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - With circus animals (2 photographs, 1 cyanotype), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - With unidentified man, in casual dress (4 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - With unidentified people, in car (4 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - BUFFALO BILL
    - Alone (2 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Arizona
      - "Boring for oil in Arizona", 1912 (Box 2, Folder 72)
        Captioned and autographed by BB.
    - Family
      - Cody, Louisa (2 photographs), 1911 Nov 25 (Box 2, Folder 73)
      - With wife Louisa "Lulu" Cody and others, Campo Bonito, Az. (9 photographs), 1911 Nov 25 (Box 2, Folder 74)
      - With wife Louisa Cody, unidentified Native Americans, and others on porch (5 photographs) (Box 2, Folder 75)
      - Young woman shooting rifle (2 photos), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - In horse-drawn carriage with unidentified man, near ticket wagon, n.d. (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - Pony express memorial, St. Joseph, Mo. (3 photographs), [1912?] (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - Posed portraits (5 photographs), n.d. (Box 2, Folder 79)
      Includes autographed carte de visite.
    - Mounted on his horse, Isham, alone and with Wild West show performers (8 photographs) (Box 2, Folder 80-82)
    - Picture postcards, 1938, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 83-84)
    - TE Ranch, captioned in ink by Buffalo Bill, n.d.
    - Touring Fort Bliss, Texas, with General Hugh L. Scott (5 photographs), [1914 Apr] (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Touring unidentified mine (8 photographs), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - With cowboy, two gentlemen, and dog sitting on rock in front of rocky hill (Box 3, Folder 87)
  - BUFFALO BILL'S WILD WEST & PAWNEE BILL'S GREAT...
    - Four unidentified men standing in front of stagecoach beside showground (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Performers (50 photographs, 6 cyanotypes), 1908 Aug, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 89-93)
      See also: Box 2, folder 67
      See also: Oversize, Box 7, folder 201
    - Views of showground (2 photographs) (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - JOHN L. SULLIVAN
    - As a young man
      - Portrait, 12 years old, [1870] (Box 3, Folder 95)
      - "John L. Sullivan, Champion of the World, Photographed One Day After the Fight in 1882 with Patty Ryan at Mississippi City", 1882 [Feb 8] (Box 3, Folder 96)
      - Portrait by J.M. Mora, bare-chested in boxing pose in ring, 1882
      - Portrait by John Wood, standing in top hat with cane, 1883 (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - As an older man
      - Feeding chickens, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 98)
      - In field on farm pointing at an unidentified workman, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 99)
      - In boxing pose, mock fighting small boy, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 100)
      - Seated on bench with two young boys on lap, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 101)
      - Seated with an unidentified gentleman at restaurant table, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 102)
      - JLS with others on parade review stand (Box 3, Folder 103)
      - "John L. Sullivan, taken on board the Ivernia, Feb 8, 1910", 1910 Feb 8 (Box 3, Folder 104)
      - Of back, walking into street, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 105)
      - Portraits alone and with wife (2 photographs) (Box 3, Folder 106)
      - Press photos by Arthur E. Dunn, photographer for the Daily News, Omaha Neb., of JLS as an older man, posed in fighting stance with another older boxer (2 photographs), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 107)
      - With wife, in front of Hollow Tree, Stanley Park, Vancouver, BC, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - Apeda Studio portraits (2 photographs), n.d. (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - Dana Photos S.F.
      - "Jeffries-Johnson, Round 15 - No. 17", [1910 July 4] (Box 3, Folder 110)
      - "No. 18. John L. Sullivan & Jordan", [1910 July 4] (Box 3, Folder 111)
      - "No. 22. Wm. Muldoon", [1910 July 4] (Box 3, Folder 112)
      - "No. 34", John L. Sullivan and other men in outdoor boxing ring, [1910 July 4] (Box 3, Folder 113)
      - "No. 37. At the Ringside, Johnson-Jeffries Contest, Reno, July 4, 1910", 1910 Jul 4 (Box 3, Folder 114)
      - "No. 78. Tommy Burns, Corbett, Jeffries, Sullivan", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Siegel Studio
      - Six photographs, 1918, n.d.
  - OTHER PHOTOGRAPHS
    - Allen & Rowell, photographers
      - Scenes from the Battle of Gettysburg painted by Paul Philippoteaux, part of a 360 degree mural cycle (4 albumen prints on mounts), [ca. 1884] (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Unidentified photographs
      - Animals (15 photographs, 10 cyanotypes), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 117-118)
      - Buildings, landscapes, and cityscapes (46 photographs, 3 cyanotypes) (Box 4, Folder 119-125)
      - Cityscape, fire in distance (3 photographs) (Box 4, Folder 126)
      - Groups (15 photographs), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 127-128)
      - Individuals (17 photographs, 6 cyanotypes) (Box 4, Folder 129-132)
      - Laborers, in desert (5 photographs) (Box 4, Folder 133)
      - Men, with buckets near house (2 photographs), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 134)
      - Miniature photographs (4 photographs, 40 cyanotypes), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 135-137)
      - Mounted (7 photographs) (Box 4, Folder 138)
      - Old man with beard (4 photographs), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 139)
      - Trains (3 photographs), n.d. (Box 4, Folder 140)
      - Train wreck with crowd of bystanders (Box 4, Folder 141)
        Caption on verso.
- Personal Papers, Date: 18-?-1919; Series III; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series III, Personal Papers, is organized by form of material, and then chronologically.
  - Business card and stationery (Box 5, Folder 142)
  - Circular: CR for Boston Common Council, [18-?] (Box 5, Folder 143)
  - Clipping, 1917 May 12 (Box 5, Folder 144)
  - Diary, 1909 (Box 5, Folder 145)
  - Diary, 1910 (Box 5, Folder 146)
  - Diary, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 147-148)
  - Diary, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 149)
  - Diary, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 150)
  - Diary, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 151)
  - Diary, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 152)
  - Diary, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 153)
  - Diary, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 154)
  - Diary, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 155)
- Business Papers, 1905-1924; Series IV; 0.21; (1 box)
  Series IV, Business Papers is organized into four subseries: High Jinks Gold Mining Company, John L. Sullivan Motion Picture, Montezuma Mining Company, Montezuma Silver Mines Corporation. Subseries are arranged by type of material.
  - HIGH JINKS GOLD MINING COMPANY
    - Appointment of Agent form (blank), [191?] (Box 5, Folder 156)
    - Articles of Incorporation: draft, typescript form completed in manuscript, 1911 Nov (Box 5, Folder 157)
    - By-Laws: draft, typescript form completed in manuscript, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 158)
    - By-Laws (3 copies), n.d. (Box 5, Folder 159)
    - Minutes: manuscript and typescript, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 160)